<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<response>
  <error><![CDATA[OK]]></error>
  <limit>20</limit>
  <number_of_page_results>8</number_of_page_results>
  <number_of_total_results>8</number_of_total_results>
  <offset>0</offset>
  <results>
    <publisher>
      <aliases><![CDATA[]]></aliases>
      <api_detail_url><![CDATA[http://api.comicvine.com/publisher/31/]]></api_detail_url>
      <date_added>2008-06-06 11:08:00.755580</date_added>
      <date_last_updated>2013-01-30 00:57:49.567163</date_last_updated>
      <deck><![CDATA[Publisher of iconic characters and teams such as Spider-Man, the Avengers, the X-Men, Iron Man, the Hulk, Thor, Captain America, Daredevil, and the Fantastic Four. One of the "big two" comic publishers along with DC Comics.]]></deck>
      <description><![CDATA[OriginCreated by current co publisher of Marvel, Stan Lee.ImprintsIcon ComicsMarvel Digital Comics UnlimitedMarvel KnightsMarvel MusicMAXSoleilUltimate MarvelHistoryIn 1939 Martin Goodman was persuaded by Frank Torpey, the sales manager of Funnies Inc. to start publishing comics. This was the start of Timely Comics Publications, which would later produce its first comic; Marvel Comics #1.Timeline1936Introduction of Ka-Zar in a pulp fiction magazine published by Manvis owned by Martin Goodman prior to founding Timely Comics. Ka-Zar was created by Bob Byrd who was the author of Ka-Zar #1. Ka-Zar's pulp fiction story would later be adapted in Marvel Comics #1.1939Founding Timely Publications.Marvel Comics #1Introduction of The Human TorchIntroduction of Sub-MarinerIntroduction of Ka-Zar in a comic bookIntroduction of The AngelIntroduction of The Mask RaiderJoe Simon is hired to be the first Editor and Chief of Timely.1940Artist Jack Kirby joins Timely's staff.Goodman hired his wife's teenage cousin, Stanley Lieber. He would later be known as Stan Lee.The "Marvel Universe" is created in when Namor and The Human Torch are in the first crossover issue.Introduction of The Thin ManIntroduction of Betty DeanIntroduction of Black WidowFirst "One off" Red Raven is introduced and the series doesn't see a second issue.The Roman gods Mercury and Pluto made an appearance in Red Raven Comics #1 (Mercury in the 20th Century)The Human Torch takes over the "Red Raven" series. Starting with The Human Torch #2. There was never a number 1.Introduction of ToroOne story of Super Hero Marvel Boy was released.Introduction of Vision .1941Introduction of Captain AmericaIntroduction of Bucky BarnesIntroduction of the PatriotTimely comics fight the Nazis.Introduction of the Red SkullIntroduction of Blue DiamondIntroduction of the FinStanley Lieber writes first story for Timely, "Captain Comic #4", under the pen name of Stan Lee.Teams All Winners and Young Allies (formerly Sentinels of Liberty) make the first of Marvel's many teams.Introduction of The WhizzerIntroduction of Jack Frost.The Human Torch #5 depicts an epic battle between The Human Torch and Namor.Introduction of Father TimeIntroduction of The DestroyerJoe Simon and Jack Kirby leave TimelyStan Lee becomes Editor-in-Chief at the young age of 18 years old.1942The December 7 1941 attack on Pearl Harbor sends several Timely members into armed services.Introduction of Citizen VIntroduction of Miss FuryVince Fago becomes Editor while Stan Lee is off at war.1943Introduction of Super Rabbit to Comedy ComicsIntroduction of Captain WonderAll Select Comics unite the big three, Captain , Sub-Mariner, and The Human Torch.Introduction of Miss1944Captain America films were released in a 15 part series.1945The end of World War 2 brought the decline of "Super Heroes" sales.Introduction of Millie the Model who spawned 207 issues.Introduction of Patsy WalkerMarvel reaches out to a young female audience.Stan Lee returns to his chair as Editor-in-Chief after the war.1946Introduction of The Blonde PhantomIntroduction of Mighty Mouse.Young Allies Comics was canceled.All Winners Squad #21 was the last issue for the team.Harvey Kurtzman starts doing freelance work for Timely comics. He would later become the original editor of MAD magazine.Gene Colan is hired as an artist for Timely.1947Introduction to NamoraAs Super Hero comic stayed in a slump, Crime, Romance, and Westerns gain in popularity1948Comic Crime-fighters and Lawbreakers Always Lose!debut to increase the popularity of the crime comics.Introduction of Two-Gun Kid.Introduction of Sun GirlIntroduction of Kid ColtIntroduction of VenusThe Super Rabbit series is canceled.John Buscema answers an ad to become one of the best know artists in Marvel's history.As Super Hero comics stayed in a slump, Crime, Romance, and Westerns gain in popularity1950'sTimely goes through an identity change. From Timely to Atlas Comics to eventually Marvel.1960'sAs super hero comics make a re-emergence Marvel comes out with it's new heroes. These heroes have more personal and emotional back stories1961 sees the creation of The Fantastic FourIn the following years (following the successful relaunch of DC's heroes ) Marvel launches the Hulk, X-Men, Iron Man, Spider-Man, Daredevil, Avengers, The return of the Golden Age Captain America, and many more.The comic-book arm of the company started in 1939 as Timely Publications, and by the 1950s was generally known as Atlas Comics. Marvel's modern incarnation dates from 1961, with the launching of Fantastic Four and other superhero titles created by Stan Lee, Jack Kirby, Steve Ditko, and others. Marvel has since become the largest American comic book publisher over long time competitor DC ComicsStan the Man.Editors-in-chiefJoe Simon (1940-1941)Stan Lee (1941-1942)Vincent Fago (acting editor during Lee's military service) (1942-1945)Stan Lee (1945-1972)Roy Thomas (1972-1974)Len Wein (1974-1975)Marv Wolfman (black-and-white magazines 1974-1975, entire line 1975-1976)Gerry Conway (1976)Archie Goodwin (1976-1978)Jim Shooter (1978-1987)Tom DeFalco (1987-1994)Bob Harras (1995-2000)Joe Quesada (2000-2011)Axel Alonso (2011-Present)Events In The Marvel Universe1990'sThe Infinity Gauntlet (1991) - Collected In TradeOperation: Galactic Storm (1992) - Collected In 2 Trades (1, 2)Infinity War (1992) - Collected In TradeX-Cutioner's Song (1992-1993) - Collected In TradeInfinity Crusade (1993) - Collected In 2 Trades (1, 2)Maximum Carnage (1993) - Collected In TradeFatal Attractions (1993) - Collected In TradePhalanx Covenant (1994) - Collected In TradeClone Saga (1994-1996) - Collected In 5 Trades (1, 2, 3, 4, 5)Age Of Apocalypse (1995) - Collected In 4 Trades (1, 2, 3, 4)Onslaught Saga (1996-1997) - Collected In 4 Trades (1, 2, 3, 4)Operation: Zero Tolerance (1997) - Collected In TradeHeroes Reborn (1996-1997) No Main Trade For EventContest Of Champions II - (1999) - Collected In Trade2000'sEve Of Destruction (2001) - Collected In TradeThe Kang Dynasty (2001-2002) - Collected In TradeInfinity Abyss (2002) - Collected In TradeAvengers Disassembled (2004) - Collected In TradeSecret War (2004-2005) - Collected In TradeHouse Of M (2005) - Collected In TradeDecimation (2005) - No Main Trade For EventAnnihilation (2006-2007) - Collected In 3 Trades (Book One, Two, Three)Civil War (2006-2007) - Collected In TradePlanet Hulk (2006-2007) - Collected In TradeAnnihilation Conquest (2007-2008) - Collected In 2 Trades (Book One, Two)World War Hulk(2007) - Collected In TradeMessiah Complex (2007-2008) - Collected In TradeOne More Day (2007-2008) - Collected In TradeSecret Invasion (2008) - Collected In TradeDark Reign (2009) - No Main Trade For EventMessiah War (2009) - Collected In TradeWar Of Kings (2009) - Collected In TradeCaptain America: Reborn (2009) - Collected In TradeUtopia (2009) - Collected In TradeNation X - (2009-2010) - Collected In TradeNecrosha (2009-2010) - Collected In TradeRealm Of Kings (2009-2010) - Collected In TradeSiege (2009-2010) - Collected In TradeFall Of The Hulks (2009-2010) - Collected In 4 Trades (One, Two, Three, Four)2010'sThe Gauntlet(2010) - Collected In 5 Trades (1, 2, 3, 4, 5)The Grim Hunt (2010) - Collected In TradeSecond Coming (2010) - Collected In TradeChildren's Crusade (2010-2011)Doomwar (2010) - Collected In TradeHeroic Age (2010) - No Main Trade For EventThe Thanos Imperative (2010) - Collected In TradeWorld War Hulks (2010) - Collected In 2 Trades (1, 2)Curse Of The Mutants (2010) - Collected In TradeShadowland (2010) - Collected In TradeChaos War (2010) - Collected In TradeThree (2010)Age Of X (2011) - Collected In TradeOnslaught Unleashed (2011)Fear Itself (2011)Spider-Island (2011)Schism (2011)Shattered Heroes (2011)Avengers Vs X-Men (2012)Marvel AnimationUltimate Avengers(2006)Ultimate Avengers 2 (2006)The Invincible Iron Man (2007)Doctor Strange: The Sorcerer Supreme (2007)Next Avengers: Heroes Of Tomorrow (2008)Hulk Vs Thor/Hulk Vs Wolverine (2009)Planet Hulk (2010)Thor: Tales Of Asgard (2011)Marvel Movies (Cinematic Releases)Howard the Duck (August 1, 1986)The Punisher (October 5, 1989)Captain America (December 14, 1990 [UK])Blade (August 21, 1998)X-Men (July 14, 2000)Blade II (March 22, 2002)Spider-Man(May 3, 2002)Daredevil (February 14, 2003)X2: X-Men United (May 2, 2003)Hulk (June 20, 2003)The Punisher (April 16, 2004)Spider-Man 2 (June 30, 2004)Blade: Trinity (December 8, 2004)Elektra (January 14, 2005)Man Thing (April 30, 2005)Fantastic Four (July 8, 2005)X-Men: The Last Stand (May 26, 2006)Ghost Rider (February 16, 2007)Spider-Man 3(May 4, 2007)Fantastic Four: Rise of the Silver Surfer (June 15, 2007)Iron Man (May 2, 2008)The Incredible Hulk (June 13, 2008)Punisher: War Zone (December 5, 2008)X-Men Origins: Wolverine(May 1, 2009)Iron Man 2 (May 7, 2010)Thor (May 6, 2011)X-Men: First Class (June 3, 2011)Captain America: The First Avenger (July 22, 2011)Ghost Rider: Spirit of Vengeance (February 17, 2012)The Avengers (May 4, 2012)The Amazing Spider-Man (July 3, 2012)Coming Attractions (Cinematic Releases)The WolverineIron Man 3 (March 3, 2013)The Wolverine (July 26, 2013)Thor: The Dark World (November 8, 2013)Captain America: The Winter Soldier (April 4, 2014)Marvel HeadquartersMarvel Superhero CharactersLocated in New York City, Marvel has been successively headquartered in the McGraw-Hill Building (where it originated as Timely Comics in 1939); in suite 1401 of the Empire State Building; at 635 Madison Avenue (the actual location, though the comic books' indicia listed the parent publishing-company's address of 625 Madison Ave.); 575 Madison Avenue; 387 Park Avenue South; 10 East 40th Street; and 417 Fifth Avenue.Marvel has had 25 television series, 34 live-action films and 72 video games based on the Marvel Universe. There are also several theme park rides based on the Universe too.]]></description>
      <id>31</id>
      <image>
        <icon_url><![CDATA[http://media.comicvine.com/uploads/8/80121/1925308-2000px_marvellogo.svg_icon.png]]></icon_url>
        <medium_url><![CDATA[http://media.comicvine.com/uploads/8/80121/1925308-2000px_marvellogo.svg_small.png]]></medium_url>
        <screen_url><![CDATA[http://media.comicvine.com/uploads/8/80121/1925308-2000px_marvellogo.svg_screen.png]]></screen_url>
        <small_url><![CDATA[http://media.comicvine.com/uploads/8/80121/1925308-2000px_marvellogo.svg_small.png]]></small_url>
        <super_url><![CDATA[http://media.comicvine.com/uploads/8/80121/1925308-2000px_marvellogo.svg_super.png]]></super_url>
        <thumb_url><![CDATA[http://media.comicvine.com/uploads/8/80121/1925308-2000px_marvellogo.svg_thumb.png]]></thumb_url>
        <tiny_url><![CDATA[http://media.comicvine.com/uploads/8/80121/1925308-2000px_marvellogo.svg_tiny.png]]></tiny_url>
      </image>
      <location_address><![CDATA[]]></location_address>
      <location_city><![CDATA[]]></location_city>
      <location_state><![CDATA[]]></location_state>
      <name><![CDATA[Marvel]]></name>
      <resource_type><![CDATA[publisher]]></resource_type>
      <site_detail_url><![CDATA[http://www.comicvine.com/marvel/57-31/]]></site_detail_url>
    </publisher>
    <publisher>
      <aliases><![CDATA[]]></aliases>
      <api_detail_url><![CDATA[http://api.comicvine.com/publisher/2699/]]></api_detail_url>
      <date_added>2010-08-13 19:30:35.092839</date_added>
      <date_last_updated>2011-10-16 10:41:32.086588</date_last_updated>
      <deck><![CDATA[Marvel Knights is a Marvel Comics imprint which deals with more mature themes than the Marvel Universe imprint, but not such adult themes as touched on by the MAX imprint.]]></deck>
      <description><![CDATA["These stand alone stories won't just challenge readers to re-think their favorite Marvel legends. Oftentimes, we'll focus on characters that are off the beaten path - boiling these archetypes down to their cores. We want to build on the tradition of limited series like Ennis and Crain's Ghost Rider, Frank Cho's Shanna, the She-Devil and Robert Rodi and Ribic's Loki -- each of which offered very distinct visions for Marvel characters, and each of which -- judging by sales numbers -- were embraced by fandom."Axel Alonso, Marvel Knights editor.Marvel Knights also became a film banner featured in mature movies like Ghost Rider 2 and Punisher:Warzone.]]></description>
      <id>2699</id>
      <image>
        <icon_url><![CDATA[http://media.comicvine.com/uploads/3/39997/1336428-marvel_mk_icon.jpg]]></icon_url>
        <medium_url><![CDATA[http://media.comicvine.com/uploads/3/39997/1336428-marvel_mk_small.jpg]]></medium_url>
        <screen_url><![CDATA[http://media.comicvine.com/uploads/3/39997/1336428-marvel_mk_screen.jpg]]></screen_url>
        <small_url><![CDATA[http://media.comicvine.com/uploads/3/39997/1336428-marvel_mk_small.jpg]]></small_url>
        <super_url><![CDATA[http://media.comicvine.com/uploads/3/39997/1336428-marvel_mk_super.jpg]]></super_url>
        <thumb_url><![CDATA[http://media.comicvine.com/uploads/3/39997/1336428-marvel_mk_thumb.jpg]]></thumb_url>
        <tiny_url><![CDATA[http://media.comicvine.com/uploads/3/39997/1336428-marvel_mk_tiny.jpg]]></tiny_url>
      </image>
      <location_address><![CDATA[]]></location_address>
      <location_city><![CDATA[]]></location_city>
      <location_state><![CDATA[]]></location_state>
      <name><![CDATA[Marvel Knights]]></name>
      <resource_type><![CDATA[publisher]]></resource_type>
      <site_detail_url><![CDATA[http://www.comicvine.com/marvel-knights/57-2699/]]></site_detail_url>
    </publisher>
    <publisher>
      <aliases><![CDATA[]]></aliases>
      <api_detail_url><![CDATA[http://api.comicvine.com/publisher/2707/]]></api_detail_url>
      <date_added>2010-08-26 20:06:14.611668</date_added>
      <date_last_updated>2010-09-04 15:48:41.274710</date_last_updated>
      <deck><![CDATA[Marvel Comics service that reprints many issues digitally from any computer and often offers online exclusive comics. ]]></deck>
      <description><![CDATA[Officially an imprint of Marvel Comics, Digital Comics Unlimited features thousands of quality scanned Marvel Comics of the past and present in an easy to read online format. For more information, visit the official site.   Digital Exclusives One perk to the service is the Digital Exclusives, stories that can only be read online.   Read It Here First Not only are previews of upcoming Marvel titles included with a subscription, but selected titles are even released early digitally - before ever reaching your local retailers shelves.  Reprints Certain Digital Exclusives have been released in physical print, usually collected in to one issue. Examples of reprinted digital material are the Galacta One Shot and Peter Parker (collections of Amazing Spider-Man Digital).]]></description>
      <id>2707</id>
      <image>
        <icon_url><![CDATA[http://media.comicvine.com/uploads/3/38780/1357386-marvel_digital_comics_unlimited_icon.jpg]]></icon_url>
        <medium_url><![CDATA[http://media.comicvine.com/uploads/3/38780/1357386-marvel_digital_comics_unlimited_small.jpg]]></medium_url>
        <screen_url><![CDATA[http://media.comicvine.com/uploads/3/38780/1357386-marvel_digital_comics_unlimited_screen.jpg]]></screen_url>
        <small_url><![CDATA[http://media.comicvine.com/uploads/3/38780/1357386-marvel_digital_comics_unlimited_small.jpg]]></small_url>
        <super_url><![CDATA[http://media.comicvine.com/uploads/3/38780/1357386-marvel_digital_comics_unlimited_super.jpg]]></super_url>
        <thumb_url><![CDATA[http://media.comicvine.com/uploads/3/38780/1357386-marvel_digital_comics_unlimited_thumb.jpg]]></thumb_url>
        <tiny_url><![CDATA[http://media.comicvine.com/uploads/3/38780/1357386-marvel_digital_comics_unlimited_tiny.jpg]]></tiny_url>
      </image>
      <location_address><![CDATA[]]></location_address>
      <location_city><![CDATA[]]></location_city>
      <location_state><![CDATA[]]></location_state>
      <name><![CDATA[Marvel Digital Comics Unlimited]]></name>
      <resource_type><![CDATA[publisher]]></resource_type>
      <site_detail_url><![CDATA[http://www.comicvine.com/marvel-digital-comics-unlimited/57-2707/]]></site_detail_url>
    </publisher>
    <publisher>
      <aliases><![CDATA[]]></aliases>
      <api_detail_url><![CDATA[http://api.comicvine.com/publisher/3318/]]></api_detail_url>
      <date_added>2012-03-14 12:30:52.052410</date_added>
      <date_last_updated>2012-03-14 12:44:54.082389</date_last_updated>
      <deck><![CDATA[Collaboration between the French publisher Soleil and Marvel.]]></deck>
      <description><![CDATA[In 2008 Marvel formed their own Soleil imprint to translate many of the French Soleil titles.By the end of 2010 all of the remaining Marvel Soleil mini-series's ended naturally but no new mini's were announced or solicited. In 2011 Marvel quietly sold off their backlog of Soleil single issues, trades and hard covers to retailers at up to 90% off cover price and in an interview Axel Alonso said that there were no plans to publish any more Soleil translations at the time. Nothing official has been said about the ending up the partnership with Soleil but the Soleil sections of the Marvel website have been shut down.]]></description>
      <id>3318</id>
      <image>
        <icon_url><![CDATA[http://media.comicvine.com/uploads/6/67397/2242981-soleil_icon.jpg]]></icon_url>
        <medium_url><![CDATA[http://media.comicvine.com/uploads/6/67397/2242981-soleil_small.jpg]]></medium_url>
        <screen_url><![CDATA[http://media.comicvine.com/uploads/6/67397/2242981-soleil_screen.jpg]]></screen_url>
        <small_url><![CDATA[http://media.comicvine.com/uploads/6/67397/2242981-soleil_small.jpg]]></small_url>
        <super_url><![CDATA[http://media.comicvine.com/uploads/6/67397/2242981-soleil_super.jpg]]></super_url>
        <thumb_url><![CDATA[http://media.comicvine.com/uploads/6/67397/2242981-soleil_thumb.jpg]]></thumb_url>
        <tiny_url><![CDATA[http://media.comicvine.com/uploads/6/67397/2242981-soleil_tiny.jpg]]></tiny_url>
      </image>
      <location_address><![CDATA[]]></location_address>
      <location_city><![CDATA[]]></location_city>
      <location_state><![CDATA[]]></location_state>
      <name><![CDATA[Marvel Soleil]]></name>
      <resource_type><![CDATA[publisher]]></resource_type>
      <site_detail_url><![CDATA[http://www.comicvine.com/marvel-soleil/57-3318/]]></site_detail_url>
    </publisher>
    <publisher>
      <aliases><![CDATA[]]></aliases>
      <api_detail_url><![CDATA[http://api.comicvine.com/publisher/2812/]]></api_detail_url>
      <date_added>2010-12-25 07:36:17.396794</date_added>
      <date_last_updated>2012-07-15 12:35:14.451503</date_last_updated>
      <deck><![CDATA[Marvel UK was an imprint launched by Marvel Comics which served as a publisher in the United Kingdom.]]></deck>
      <description><![CDATA[OriginDuring the 1950s and 1960s a number of UK companies including Alan Class Comics and Odhams Press licensed the rights to reprint first Atlas and later Marvel Comics American-originated material, while companies such as World Distributors held separate licenses to reprint US Marvel comics reformatted for the British annuals market. Their success prompted Marvel to start up their own UK branch, Marvel UK, in 1972 to cut out the middlemen and directly reprint American strips.Like most other UK comics, Marvel UK's titles were black and white weekly anthologies, reprinting several US strips in installments; in order to split up American comics which were between 18 and 22 pages in length into 2 to 5 page segments while still making sense and ending each week on suitable high points, panels and text were frequently rearranged or removed altogether, and it was not uncommon for new splash pages to be drawn by UK artists to properly recap the start of each segment. The first comic was Mighty World of Marvel, reprinting the Hulk, Spider-Man and Fantastic Four, but early in 1973 Spider-Man was split off into his own title, Spider-Man Comics Weekly, which would prove the most enduring of all Marvel UK's titles, lasting until 1985 and issue #666, undertaking through a variety of title variations and merging with several less successful titles during its run. Several other titles were soon launched, including Avengers, Planet of the Apes, Dracula Lives!, The Super-Heroes, Savage Sword of Conan and The Titans, and though most were short lived, failing titles were inevitably replaced by new ones.However, Marvel UK began to hit a number of problems. First, being published weekly meant that in some cases the reprint material would run out as the UK caught up with the matching US title; while sometimes this would prompt a break in the run of a given strip, a more innovative approach was tried when Planet of the Apes hit this problem, and copies of Killraven's escapades from Amazing Adventures were redrawn and relettered to give Killraven black hair and to pit him against Apes instead of Martians, as the renamed Apeslayer. The second problem was that the most popular US material was soon used up, prompting Marvel UK to increasingly have to populate their titles with Marvel's poorer selling material. With the UK market nevertheless proving lucrative, the decision was made to provide Marvel UK with a strip aimed specifically at the UK audience, though the creative team were all Americans, and so in 1976 a weekly Captain Britain comic was launched; the other strips within - Nick Fury, Agent of S.H.I.E.L.D. and Fantastic Four - remained US reprints. Though popular for a while, it was not an unqualified success, and Captain Britain's comic was soon absorbed into Super Spider-Man and Captain Britain (the title formerly known as Spider-Man Comic), where the British hero stayed for a few more stories before being replaced by reprints again. The mid-1970s also saw Marvel do a deal with new annuals publisher Grandreams, resulting in the co-publication of Marvel Annuals, bringing that license in-house. And all the meantime Marvel UK continued to launch new titles reprinting Marvel US material, such as Rampage, Fury and Star Wars Weekly.In 1979 new Marvel UK editor-in-chief Dez Skinn was asked to revamp the now-ailing line. His solutions included commissioning material from UK writers and artists and begin producing new strips, several of which were launched in Hulk Comic (later Hulk Weekly and later still Incredible Hulk); Captain Britain returned as an ongoing co-star in the UK's new Black Knight strip, alongside prohibition-era vigilante Night Raven, and new UK-penned tales of US heroes the Hulk and Nick Fury. Skinn also arranged a deal with the BBC to publish a tie-in comic with the popular Dr. Who TV series; though the Doctor had previously enjoyed comic strip adventures in several titles over the years, this marked the first time he had his own comic entirely devoted to him. Doctor Who Weekly was launched in 1979, and though it has changed its name to Doctor Who Monthly and then Doctor Who Magazine over the years, and switched publishers to Panini, it is still being published and is now the longest-running TV tie-in magazine in the world. From this point on, while most of Marvel UK's output would remain reprints through the 1980s, it would be continuously producing new material, both set in the Marvel Universe and for tie-in comics to various TV shows, including SF drama Blake's 7, children's show Worzel Gummidge and others.After Hulk Comic reached the end of its run both Captain Britain and Night Raven endured, the former in his own strip drawn by Alan Davis and initially written by David Thorpe, and subsequently by Alan Moore, and the latter in text stories that jumped from title to title. Captain Britain's story would move from Marvel Super-Heroes to The Daredevils and eventually Mighty World of Marvel, before Moore's story ended. Jamie Delano joined Alan Davis in picking up the hero's story following this, and a few issues later Captain Britain regained his own title, at least for a while.Another prominent, if unexpected, title to produce acclaimed new material was Transformers, where again the reprint material kept running out as the UK caught up with the US comic, resulting in a huge percentage of new UK material, most written by Simon Furman. These new stories would see the debut of Death's Head, a mercenary cyborg who would subsequently transfer over to the regular Marvel universe.The company had a major growth in the early 1990's when it came up with many new heroes such as a reinvented Death's Head II, Hell's Angel (soon retitled Dark Angel) Motormouth, the Knights of Pendragon and Warheads. These series were extremely popular for a few months, but in 1994 Marvel UK became a victim of Marvel US' financial woes. Almost all Marvel UK's series where canceled at the end of 1994 and Marvel UK was sold to their distributor, Panini, who took over reprinting US Marvel titles for the British market.Marvel UK's legacyPerhaps not as famous as the American Marvel Comics, Marvel UK did make a large footprint in history by creating characters that are still used to this day.Famous comic book characters such as Captain Britain, Psylocke, Meggan, the Technet team, the Fury and Courtney Ross all first appeared in Marvel UK comics before they made their American debut. Also prominent writers and artists such as Alan Moore, Grant Morrison, Gary Frank and Mark Miller had some of their earliest work published by Marvel UK before breaking into the US market.]]></description>
      <id>2812</id>
      <image>
        <icon_url><![CDATA[http://media.comicvine.com/uploads/8/81501/1803236-marvel_uk_icon.jpg]]></icon_url>
        <medium_url><![CDATA[http://media.comicvine.com/uploads/8/81501/1803236-marvel_uk_small.jpg]]></medium_url>
        <screen_url><![CDATA[http://media.comicvine.com/uploads/8/81501/1803236-marvel_uk_screen.jpg]]></screen_url>
        <small_url><![CDATA[http://media.comicvine.com/uploads/8/81501/1803236-marvel_uk_small.jpg]]></small_url>
        <super_url><![CDATA[http://media.comicvine.com/uploads/8/81501/1803236-marvel_uk_super.jpg]]></super_url>
        <thumb_url><![CDATA[http://media.comicvine.com/uploads/8/81501/1803236-marvel_uk_thumb.jpg]]></thumb_url>
        <tiny_url><![CDATA[http://media.comicvine.com/uploads/8/81501/1803236-marvel_uk_tiny.jpg]]></tiny_url>
      </image>
      <location_address><![CDATA[]]></location_address>
      <location_city><![CDATA[]]></location_city>
      <location_state><![CDATA[]]></location_state>
      <name><![CDATA[Marvel UK]]></name>
      <resource_type><![CDATA[publisher]]></resource_type>
      <site_detail_url><![CDATA[http://www.comicvine.com/marvel-uk/57-2812/]]></site_detail_url>
    </publisher>
    <publisher>
      <aliases><![CDATA[]]></aliases>
      <api_detail_url><![CDATA[http://api.comicvine.com/publisher/2547/]]></api_detail_url>
      <date_added>2010-01-23 21:13:47.930263</date_added>
      <date_last_updated>2013-01-01 12:01:34.753754</date_last_updated>
      <deck><![CDATA[Short lived Marvel Comics imprint that focused on music-themed comics.]]></deck>
      <description><![CDATA[Brief HistoryThe imprint existed in the early to mid 1990's and focussed on comics for music-related characters. The main example was a comic based on Alice Cooper. A handfull of other comics where published under the imprint until it was cancelled.]]></description>
      <id>2547</id>
      <image>
        <icon_url><![CDATA[http://media.comicvine.com/uploads/1/15238/1272643-marvel_music_icon.jpg]]></icon_url>
        <medium_url><![CDATA[http://media.comicvine.com/uploads/1/15238/1272643-marvel_music_small.jpg]]></medium_url>
        <screen_url><![CDATA[http://media.comicvine.com/uploads/1/15238/1272643-marvel_music_screen.jpg]]></screen_url>
        <small_url><![CDATA[http://media.comicvine.com/uploads/1/15238/1272643-marvel_music_small.jpg]]></small_url>
        <super_url><![CDATA[http://media.comicvine.com/uploads/1/15238/1272643-marvel_music_super.jpg]]></super_url>
        <thumb_url><![CDATA[http://media.comicvine.com/uploads/1/15238/1272643-marvel_music_thumb.jpg]]></thumb_url>
        <tiny_url><![CDATA[http://media.comicvine.com/uploads/1/15238/1272643-marvel_music_tiny.jpg]]></tiny_url>
      </image>
      <location_address><![CDATA[]]></location_address>
      <location_city><![CDATA[]]></location_city>
      <location_state><![CDATA[]]></location_state>
      <name><![CDATA[Marvel Music]]></name>
      <resource_type><![CDATA[publisher]]></resource_type>
      <site_detail_url><![CDATA[http://www.comicvine.com/marvel-music/57-2547/]]></site_detail_url>
    </publisher>
    <publisher>
      <aliases><![CDATA[]]></aliases>
      <api_detail_url><![CDATA[http://api.comicvine.com/publisher/2961/]]></api_detail_url>
      <date_added>2011-06-16 04:36:40.286643</date_added>
      <date_last_updated>2011-10-21 12:18:57.449845</date_last_updated>
      <deck><![CDATA[Marvel Italia is the Italian division of Marvel Comics]]></deck>
      <description><![CDATA[OriginMarvel italia was born in the spring of 1994 as one of the European subsidiaries of the publisher of Marvel Comics and Marvel's first piece of the future Europe.In 1999, the restructuring of the Marvel Comic ends, and is decided on the sale of Panini.The property of Panini S.p.A. Italian returns, and the two companies to separate return.Panini keeps intact the management staff who had managed the company under the ownership of Marvel, and so is the publishing division, which continues to be called Marvel Italia.]]></description>
      <id>2961</id>
      <image>
        <icon_url><![CDATA[http://media.comicvine.com/uploads/9/96457/1863203-logomarvelitalia_2_icon.jpg]]></icon_url>
        <medium_url><![CDATA[http://media.comicvine.com/uploads/9/96457/1863203-logomarvelitalia_2_small.jpg]]></medium_url>
        <screen_url><![CDATA[http://media.comicvine.com/uploads/9/96457/1863203-logomarvelitalia_2_screen.jpg]]></screen_url>
        <small_url><![CDATA[http://media.comicvine.com/uploads/9/96457/1863203-logomarvelitalia_2_small.jpg]]></small_url>
        <super_url><![CDATA[http://media.comicvine.com/uploads/9/96457/1863203-logomarvelitalia_2_super.jpg]]></super_url>
        <thumb_url><![CDATA[http://media.comicvine.com/uploads/9/96457/1863203-logomarvelitalia_2_thumb.jpg]]></thumb_url>
        <tiny_url><![CDATA[http://media.comicvine.com/uploads/9/96457/1863203-logomarvelitalia_2_tiny.jpg]]></tiny_url>
      </image>
      <location_address><![CDATA[]]></location_address>
      <location_city><![CDATA[]]></location_city>
      <location_state><![CDATA[]]></location_state>
      <name><![CDATA[Marvel Italia]]></name>
      <resource_type><![CDATA[publisher]]></resource_type>
      <site_detail_url><![CDATA[http://www.comicvine.com/marvel-italia/57-2961/]]></site_detail_url>
    </publisher>
    <publisher>
      <aliases><![CDATA[]]></aliases>
      <api_detail_url><![CDATA[http://api.comicvine.com/publisher/3520/]]></api_detail_url>
      <date_added>2012-07-08 04:46:25.487917</date_added>
      <date_last_updated>2012-07-08 04:46:25.554191</date_last_updated>
      <deck><![CDATA[Small self publisher of Marvelmania Magazine]]></deck>
      <description><![CDATA[]]></description>
      <id>3520</id>
      <image></image>
      <location_address><![CDATA[]]></location_address>
      <location_city><![CDATA[]]></location_city>
      <location_state><![CDATA[]]></location_state>
      <name><![CDATA[Marvelmania International]]></name>
      <resource_type><![CDATA[publisher]]></resource_type>
      <site_detail_url><![CDATA[http://www.comicvine.com/marvelmania-international/57-3520/]]></site_detail_url>
    </publisher>
  </results>
  <status_code>1</status_code>
</response>